

SHAZID HASAN RIAM

Graphic & UI Designer Front-End Developer

ABOUT ME

Creative Graphic and User Interface Designer & Front-End Developer with two years facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software. Experienced in designing print and digital media materials. Maintains user-centric designs while adhering to prescribed interface principles and related development goals. Efficient problem solver with skills in teamwork and delivering projects on time.

CONTACT ME

Phone: 01717 435 769 01600 009 785

Address:

House: 21, Road: 05, Block: B, Banasree, Rampura, Dhaka - 1219

Email:

shazidhasanriam@gmail.com shazid.riam@northsouth.edu

EXPERIENCE

MAR, 2021 - OCT, 2021

User Interface Designer

Ghuddy Limited

- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- · Analyzed existing interfaces to detect user pain points, recommending design changes and iterative updates to the IT manager.

NOV, 2019 - FEB, 2020

Graphic Designer

North South University

- · Worked with clients to gather and define requirements, establish scopes and managing project milestones.
- Designed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks.
- Completed in-depth product design tests with help of different software, models and design systems.

PUBLICATION

01. Mohammad Ashraful Haque Abir, Golam Kibria Anik, Shazid Hasan Riam, Mohammed Ariful Karim, Azizul Hakim Tareq, Rashedur M. Rahman, Skin Disease Classification Using Machine Learning Techniques - IWANN 2021: International Work Conference on Artificial Neural Networks DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-85030-2_49

PROJECTS

Personal Website

- I have designed the user interface of my website using Adobe XD
- Developed the website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- The website is responsive for various devices
- Available light and dark mode
- Multiple color themes are available

Languages/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Link: https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/PersonalPortfolio/

Bookmark Manager

- · Users can manage all their bookmarks in one place
- Easy to add and remove bookmarks
- Bookmarks are saved on the local device

Languages/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Link: https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/BookmarkManager/

Form Validator

- · Basic form validation for signing up
- Ensures email, website, phone number is in the correct format
- · Check and confirm password while creating

Languages/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Link: https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/FormValidator/

EDUCATION

APR, 2016 - JAN, 2022

B.Sc - Computer Science & Engineering

North South University CGPA: 3.03 (83% Marks)

JAN, 2011 - MAR, 2013

SSC - Science

Bindu Basini Govt. Boys' High School

GPA: 5.00

APR, 2013 - MAR, 2015

HSC - Science

Major General Mahmudul Hasan Adarsha College GPA: 5.00

PORTFOLIO

Behance:

https://www.behance.net/shazidhasanriam

Github:

https://github.com/ShazidHasanRiam

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shazidhasanriam

Portfolio Website:

https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/PersonalPortfolio

HOBBIES

Cycling Travelling Photography

SKILLS

Graphic Design

• Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom

User Interface Design

• Adobe XD

Front-End Development

• HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

TRAININGS

JUL 25, 2017 - NOV 11, 2017

Graphics & Web UI Design

BASIS Institute Of Technology & Management

Duration: 140 Hours

MAR, 2018 - SEP, 2018

Graphics & UI Design

Shikhbe Shobai Duration: 4 Months

REFERENCE

Saiful Haque Miraz

Founder & CEO Ghuddy Limited Phone: 01717 855 156 Email: miraz@ghuddy.com